Jinhyuk Yoon

POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory

Rooms 011, Science Building 4, 77 Cheongam-Ro, Nam-Gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I'm an interaction designer and engineer building interactive experience through tactile manipulation. I'm interested in a tactile interface which would bridge between the world of digital and analog to bring a new paradigm of education. To broaden an insight for education, I've been participating in various projects such as start-up business, talk, performance, volunteer and art work. With deep interests in technology and education, I have been trying to create meaningful experience.

Professional Experience

POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory

Feb 2019 - Present

Research Intern

Developing a pneumatic haptic device to provide interactive tactile experiences.

Geekble Mar 2019 – Present

Communications Manager

Designing contents for interactive education business which provide playful and empirical knowledge related to science and engineering.

Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab

Jan 2019 – Feb 2019

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyzed mechanical property of spring and damper hinge mounted in oven door. Deployed the analysis result on interactive data platform to simplify design process.

Sovoro Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX research and design of the service, catalog design, and market research. Engaged in business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 – Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed science street performance, and staged science play only for adult as a finalist of the FameLab Korea and a science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Aug 2017 – Sep 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

Leadership Experience

POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2016 – Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

POSTECH, Student Election Committee

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Minor in Industrial Management Engineering. Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude*

Awards and Honors

| Commission Letter Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator | 2016 |
|--|------------|
| Finalist Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 rd FameLab Korea | 2016 |
| Runners Up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council | 2017 |
| Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH | 2015 |
| Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering | 2015, 2016 |
| The 4 th Prize The 2 nd POSTECH Hackathon | 2016 |

| National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation | 2016 – Present |
|---|----------------|
| KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH | 2016 |
| ligok Scholarship | 2014 – 2016 |

Skills and Tools

Programming Language

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

Graphic Design

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

3D Design & Analysis

Solidworks, NX

POSTECH

Selected Talks

| 2018 |
|----------------------------|
| 2016 |
| 2016 |
| 2018 |
| 2017 |
| 2016 |
| 2017 |
| 2017 |
| 2017 |
| 2 2 2 2 2 2 |